A Guide to the Ann A. Hertzler Collection, 1863-2013 (Bulk 1974-2000)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series IV: Project/Subject Files, 1982-2013
  - Subseries A: Presentation and Project Materials
    - "Cookbooks" Slide Set and Presentation Notes (Ann Hertzler and Jean Robbins) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Healthy Heart Snack Choices Resource Guide, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Grant and Fellowship Information, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "I've Been Working in the Kitchen" Project, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Presentation slides available online.
    - "I've Been Working in the Kitchen" Slides and Cassette Tape, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Nourishing Children with Books" Project, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Nutrition Instructional Publications and Handouts (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Operation Risk"/Safe Food Handling Materials, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Operation Risk" Video and Cassette Tape, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Peacock Harper Culinary Friends Collection, 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Putting the Pyramid Into Practice" Slide Set (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Teaching Children Personal and Household Responsibilities" Script, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Technology and Nutrition" Slides, 1998 (Box 7)
      Available online.
    - "What's in a Meal? A Resource Manual for the Child and Adult Care Food Program"/Food Planning, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Spencer, Ethel, and Jolene Campbell. 1982. "Snack Ideas for Day Care Centers."
      Molofsky, Anne Jacobs. 1988. Feeding Infants: A Guide for Use in the Child Care Food Program. [Alexandria, Va.]: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service.
      A Planning Guide for Food Service in Child Care Centers. 1989. [Washington, D.C.?]: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service.
    - "What's in a Meal? A Resource Manual for the Child and Adult Care Food Program"/Food Planning, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      United States. 1992. Building for the Future: Nutrition Guidance for the Child Nutrition Programs: Guidance for the Promotion of Healthy Eating for Children and Teens Participating in the U.S. Department of Agriculture's Child Nutrition Programs. [Alexandria, VA] (3101 Park Center Dr., Alexandria 22302): U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service.
      United States. 1993. Making Healthy Food Choices. Home and garden bulletin, no. 250. [Hyattsville, Md.?]: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Human Nutrition Information Service.
      Child and Adult Care Food Program, Virginia. 1993. Nibble, Slurp and Crunch: Creditable Snacks that Deal with Themes. Virginia. Mid-Atlantic Region, Food and Nutrition Service, Dept. of Agriculture.
      Child Nutrition Programs (U.S.). 1994. What's in a Meal?: A Resource Manual for Providing Nutritious Meals in the Child and Adult Care Food Program. Chicago, Ill. (77 W. Jackson Blvd., 20th Floor, Chicago 60604-1937): U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service, Midwest Region, Child Nutrition Programs.
    - "What's in a Meal? A Resource Manual for the Child and Adult Care Food Program"/Food Planning, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      United States. 1995. Child and Adult Care Food Program: Nutrition Guidance for Child Care Centers. [Alexandria, VA]: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Food and Consumer Service.
      United States. 1995. Child and Adult Care Food Program: Nutrition Guidance for Child Care Homes. [Alexandria, VA]: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Food and Consumer Service.
      United States. 1995. Nutrition and Your Health: Dietary Guidelines for Americans. Home and Garden Bulletin, no. 232. [Washington, D.C.?]: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture.
    - "What's in a Meal? A Resource Manual for the Child and Adult Care Food Program"/Food Planning, 1995,1998, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Texas. 1995. Standardized Ethnic Recipes for Child-care Centers and Family Day Homes. Austin, Tex: Texas NET.
      Child and Adult Care Food Program, Virginia. 1998. Crediting Foods in the Child and Adult Care Food Program. Virginia. Mid-Atlantic Region, Food and Nutrition Service, Dept. of Agriculture.
      Child and Adult Care Food Program, Virginia. "Developing Cycle Menus." Virginia. Mid-Atlantic Region, Food and Nutrition Service, Dept. of Agriculture.
  - Subseries B: Subject Files on Cooperative Extension and Nutrition Topics
    - Children's Nutrition (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Food Labels, 1992-1995, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1-2 (2 folders))
    - Osteoporosis, 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - USDA Team Nutrition Calendar Companion, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Cooperative Extension Media Relations, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Cooperative Extension Training, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Cooperative Extension Training, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Subject Files on Food and People (Specific and General)
    - M. A. Buie (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Fannie Farmer (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Indians (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Rachel A. Katelaars (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kooner Festivities (Box 13, Folder 6-8 (3 folders))
    - Nurses (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Subseries D: Subject Files on Foods
    - BBQ (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Butter and Sugar (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Christmas Foods (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Coffee and Tea (Box 13, Folder 13-14 (2 folders))
    - Cornbread and Popcorn (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Custard and Pudding (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Gingerbread (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Goose (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Hardtack (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Jell-O (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Lemons (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Peanuts (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Pearl Ash and Other Leavening Agents (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Rice (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Salt (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - She-Crab (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Spices (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Syllabub (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Vanilla (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Vegetables (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Victorian Funeral Foods (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Waffles (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Whiskey (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Subseries E: Subject Files on Home & Household
    - Kitchen Utensils (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Soap (see also disk in Kitchen Utensils folder) (Box 13, Folder 35)
- Series V: Posters and Oversize Publications, 1989-1996 (Folder 1)
  Frank Schaffer Publications. 1989. "The Human Skeleton." [Palos Verdes Estates, Calif.]: Frank Schaffer Publications.
  Carson-Dellosa Publishers. 1995. [Vegetables]. Picture Perfect Chartlet. [Greensboro, N.C.]: Carson-Dellosa Pub.
  Scholastic, Inc. 1995. "Sense-ational Food.". Poster includes nutrition information sheets for parents on the verso. Available online.
  Andersen, Dennis Richard, Amy Glaser Gage, and Chris L. Demarest. 1996. Big news! Straight from the Heart. [Dallas, Tex.]: American Heart Association. (3 copies)
  "Versatile Vegetables: See How They Grow." undated. Available online.
- Series VI: Artifacts, c.1863, 1993, undated
  - Food FUNdamentals National Nutrition Month partnership kit (framed), 1993 (Box 9)
  - Food and Nutrition Pins and Keychains (Box 10)
  - Gelatin mold and small antique sewing cabinet (Box 8)
  - Grocery Shopping Set (Box 10)
  - International Bread Set; Bread Set (Box 10)
  - Magnets: Characters and Kitchen Appliances (Box 14)
  - Magnets: Food Products (1 of 2) (Box 14)
  - Magnets: Food Products (2 of 2) (Box 14)
  - Nutrition magnets (Box 10)
  - Native American doll (Box 11)
  - 19th century stove (Object 3)
  - Silver cup from the Peacock Harper Culinary Friends (Box 11)
  - Stone jar and lid, c.1863 (Object 1)
  - Tea kettle (Object 2)
  - "What We Eat in America 1994-1996" mug (Box 10)